(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
いっせーので鳴り響いたスタートの合図
With a \"Ready, set, go!\", the starting signal resounded
何度と線で結んだ世界 色付けてく
Adding color to the world we connected with lines over and over
ここから
From right here
かくれんぼ
[Song: Hide-and-Seek]
物心が付く頃 すでにここにあった
By the time I was old enough to understand, it was already here
邪魔な誰かの記憶は
Annoying memories of someone...
夕日と共に蘇る
...are revived along with the setting sun.
古ぼけた絵本を飛び出して
Jumping out of an old, worn-out picture book,
落書きの中に一つの答えを見つけた
I found a single answer within the scribbles.
自分の価値に目を疑って どこまでだって落ちていけるの
Doubting my own worth, wondering how far down I can fall.
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい こんな世界じゃ僕は要らない
I want to disappear somewhere far away; in a world like this, I'm not needed.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun!
いるよ
It's already started!
いっせーので声を上げて
Ready, set, raise your voice!
聞こえてくるんだ
I can hear it coming.
自分の影の長さに気付くのも こんな時間だ
It's at this time of day that I notice the length of my own shadow.
一等星が顔を出した
The brightest star has shown its face,
届きそうで手を伸ばした
looking close enough that I reached my hand out to it.
次は僕についてきなよと 暗闇でも
Telling me "follow me next time," even in the darkness.
もう一回 まだだよ
One more time, "Not yet!"
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has begun to rise.
もう一回 まだだよ
One more time, "Not yet!"
色づいていく ここから
Coloring in from here on.
10年後の僕らは すれ違いばかりで
Ten years from now, we keep passing each other by.
喧騒に思いを馳せては 戻れない そう思い込んだ
Getting lost in the hustle and bustle, thinking we can never go back.
くたびれた心に追いつく あの頃と変わらない夕日も
Caught up to my worn-out heart, even the setting sun that hasn't changed since then...
なんとも思わない
...doesn't make me feel anything anymore.
自分を信じ歩いていければ どこまでだって登れるのにな
If only I could believe in myself and keep walking, I could climb to anywhere...
立ち止まる その空白に 大切なもの見落としている
In that empty pause where I stop, I am overlooking what's important.
見つけられないと泣き喚く君へ
To you, who cries out that you can't find it...
いっせーので声を上げて
Ready, set, raise your voice!
聞こえてくるんだ
I can hear it coming.
自分の影の長さに気付くのも こんな時間だ
It's at this time of day that I notice the length of my own shadow.
一等賞で駆け抜ける君
You, who runs through in first place,
くっついていただけの僕でも
even though I was just clinging on.
君の前を歩けるかな こんな頼りない僕でも
I wonder if I can walk in front of you, even though I'm so unreliable.
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま 無くした
The treasure chest remained covered in dust and got lost.
鍵はずっと 君のポケットの中にあった
But the key was always inside your pocket.
散らばってたすべてが今一つに重なる
Everything that was scattered is now overlapping into one.
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's take hands and begin our story.
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま 無くした (いらない かくした)
The treasure chest remained covered in dust and got lost (Unneeded, hidden...)
鍵はずっと 君のポケットの中にあった (みつけた 手を伸ばした)
But the key was always inside your pocket (...found it, reached out...)
散らばってたすべてが今愛おしくて (君と 愛おしくて)
Everything that was scattered is now precious (...with you, so precious.)
今一つに重なる
Now overlapping into one.
かけ声はいつも
The shouting cheer is always...
いっせーので声を上げて保存する
Ready, set, raise your voice!
いっせーので声を上げて 聞こえてくるんだよ
Ready, set, raise your voice! I can hear it coming.
自分の影の長さに気付くのも こんな時間だ
It's at this time of day that I notice the length of my own shadow.
一等賞で駆け抜ける君
You, who runs through in first place,
届きそうで手を伸ばした
looking close enough that I reached my hand out to you.
次は僕についてきなよと 暗闇でも
Telling me "follow me next time," even in the darkness.
もう一回 まだだよ
One more time, "Not yet!"
泣きたくなる声で
With a voice that makes me want to cry.
もう一回 まだだよ
One more time, "Not yet!"
笑う君が見えた
I saw you smiling.
もう一回 まだだよ 幕は上がりだした
One more time, "Not yet!" The curtain has begun to rise.
もう一回 もういいよ
One more time, "Ready or not!"
色づいていく ここから
Coloring in from here on.
曇天
[Song: Cloudy Weather] (Donten)
鉛の空重く垂れ込み
The leaden sky hangs low and heavy
真白に淀んだ太陽が砕けて
The pure white, stagnant sun shatters
耳鳴りを尖らせる
Sharpening the ringing in my ears
ひゅるりひゅるり低い燕が
Swooping and swirling, low-flying swallows
８の字なぞってビルの谷間を駆ける
Trace figure eights as they race through the valley of buildings
もうじきに夕立が来る
A sudden evening shower will be here soon
曇天の道を傘を忘れて
Walking along a cloudy road, forgetting her umbrella,
歩く彼女は雨に怯えている
she walks, terrified of the rain
ので 僕も弱虫ぶら下げて
So, carrying my own cowardice along,
空を仰ぐ
I look up at the sky
あちらこちらあんよは上手
Toddling here and there, walking so well
珈琲屋に寄って一休み決めたら
Stopping by a coffee shop, once I decide to take a break
帰らない 帰られない
I won't go home, I can't go home
曇天の道をぶらりぶらぶら
Strolling aimlessly along a cloudy road,
歩く二人は足軽のごとく
the two walk like foot soldiers
危険好きの誰かのふりをする
Pretending to be some daredevil,
小心者ども
cowards that we are
曇天の道を傘を忘れて
Walking along a cloudy road, forgetting her umbrella,
歩く彼女は雨に怯えている
she walks, terrified of the rain
ので 僕も弱虫ぶら下げて
So, carrying my own cowardice along,
空を仰ぐ
I look up at the sky
ほっといて育つもの なんだなんだろう？
Things that grow if you leave them alone, what on earth is that?
one more chance, one more chance
never never give up!
never give up!
運営さんなんか放送、エコーが切れてるかもしれないとのことで、確認お願いします！
Staff, it seems the broadcast echo might be turned off, so please check it!
出会いましては簡単すぎるよ
A pleasure to meet you is too simple
最初に決めた答えはひとつ
There's only one answer decided at first
ときめきました合格しますか？
My heart fluttered, will I pass the exam?
恋も勝負もあわてない
Don't rush when it comes to love or matches
コツコツコツと徹夜に溜息
Working steadily through the night with a sigh
私のなかに天才 dreamer
There's a genius dreamer inside of me
思うことみな叶えばいいな
I hope everything I think of comes true
他人の世界は気にしない
I don't care about anyone else's world
Perfect-area complete!
絶対ここで待ってるんだ
I'll definitely be waiting right here
Perfect-area 望む声が聞こえるよ
I can hear the voices wishing for a perfect-area
Ah! Yeah Yeah!!
Fight! とまらない すれちがい
Fight! An unstoppable misunderstanding
私が存在してるなら
If I am indeed here
友達かい？ 友達です！
Are we friends? Yes, we are friends!
悲しきレッテルのね
Such a sad label, you know
やり直し
Let's redo it
書き直し
Rewrite it
本気では満足しちゃ
If we are serious, we shouldn't be satisfied...
今より素敵な未来があるのに
Even though there's a more wonderful future than now
今より素敵に My life My life My life
More wonderfully than now, my life, my life, my life!
ありがとうございます！みんなもありがとう！
Thank you very much! Thank you everyone, too!
うるみましては月に星にも
My eyes welled up, looking at the moon and stars
科学的にはどうにもならず
Scientifically, nothing can be done about it
輝きました明日を夢見て
Dreaming of a shining tomorrow
恋で我慢を学んだね
I learned patience through love, didn't I?
ムクムクムクと広がる雨雲
Rain clouds expanding billowingly
私を濡らす瞬間スコール
A sudden squall soaking me in an instant
悩み事ほら流れたみたい
Look, it seems my worries have washed away
泣き言なんて忘れよう (よしっ！)
Let's forget all about whining! (Alright!)
First-nature conversation
感動したい もっとずっと
I want to be moved, much more and forever
First-nature 自分次第
First-nature, it's up to myself
変われるよ
I can change!
はーい！いいよ いいよ わー！
Yes! Good, good, wow!
さりげなく聞いてみた
I casually tried to ask...
私の勉強不足って
...Is it possible that...
可能性ありますか？
...I'm just lacking in study?
試験はナンセンスかな？イェーイ！
Is a test nonsense? Yay!
誰だって 君だって
Anyone, even you...
似合うデコレーションあるでしょう
...has a decoration that suits them, right?
これから始まる季節に挨拶
Greeting the season that's about to begin,
これから始める my life, my life, my life!
starting from now, my life, my life, my life!
気がついたときには 生まれてた
By the time I realized it, I was born.
なぜだろう さあね
Why is that? Who knows.
意識がもう育ちつつあるよ
My consciousness is already growing...
強く強くね
...strongly, strongly.
わーい！とまらないこの気持ち
Yay! This feeling won't stop!
私の勉強不足って
Is it possible that...
可能性ありますか？
...I'm just lacking in study?
それとも零点かな？ノー！
Or is it a zero score? No!
やり直し 書き直し
Redoing, rewriting...
本気でワンチャンある！？
...is there seriously a chance!?
今より素敵な未来があるから
Because there is a brighter future than now,
今より素敵に my life, my life, my life!
more beautifully than now, my life, my life, my life!
はい！というわけで始まりました！
Yes! And so it has begun!
2026桃鈴ねね誕生日、イェーイ！
2026 Momosuzu Nene's Birthday, yay!
みんな、コメントも見えてるよ、ありがとう！
Everyone, I can see your comments too, thank you!
エゴサ気づいてくれた人ありがとう
Thank you to those who noticed my egosearch.
ねね、コメントないと死んじゃう病気だから
Because Nene will die if there are no comments!
はい、というわけで、今回のハッシュタグはこちら！
Yes! And so, here is the hashtag for this time!
「#桃鈴ねね誕生日ライブ2026」です！
"#桃鈴ねね誕生日ライブ2026"!
今ね、エゴサのね、画面がちょっとバグっちゃってるんで
Right now, my egosearch screen is lagging a bit,
こっちでツイートしてくれたらめっちゃ嬉しいです！
so I'd be super happy if you could tweet with this!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
今日はね、超重大告知があるんで
Today, we have a super major announcement,
最後まで楽しんでいってください！
so please enjoy until the very end!
さあ、今3曲お聞きいただいたんですけど
Now, you've just heard three songs.
ねねの好きな、あの曲
Nene's favorite songs...
銀魂、バカテス、っていう感じで
...Gintama, Baka and Test, like that.
もうねねの好きな曲しかない3曲をやりましたけど
I performed three songs that are nothing but my favorites,
3曲目に一番歌がキツいの持ってきちゃって
but I put the hardest song to sing as the third one,
ゼハゼハでございます
so I'm completely out of breath!
というわけで、ここからはゲストパートに入っていきます！
And so, from here on, we'll enter the guest part!
それじゃあ、VTR...
Now then, the video...
レッツゴー！
...let's go!
抱きしめたいんだ
I want to hold you tight!
噛みしめたいんだ
I want to savor it!
驚かしたいんだ
I want to surprise you!
今は眩しいよ COOLISH WALK
Right now, it's dazzling, COOLISH WALK!
一、朝食が大事です
1. Breakfast is important!
二、迷う心を抑えて
2. Hold back your hesitating heart!
三、非凡人になりましょう
3. Let's become extraordinary people!
四、ハイビートなら救われる
4. If it's a high beat, you'll be saved!
青い二人のヘブン
The blue heaven of us two...
恋人になる夢はレア
...the dream of becoming lovers is rare.
愉快 特盛のうのう
Enjoying a super-sized, carefree life,
トレースして 空を駆け回りたい
trace it, I want to run around the sky!
揺れる思いの下
Beneath my swaying feelings,
トッピングには 恋のインターセプト
the topping is love's intercept.
膨らんでる すごいメニューを作る
I'll create a swelling, amazing menu,
とやかく言うなら 丸ごとフルーツ 育みましょう
if you complain, let's grow whole fruits!
高まりたいんだ
I want to get excited!
味わいたいんだ
I want to taste it!
おたけびたいんだ
I want to roar!
そんな夢を見て COOLISH WALK
With dreams like that, COOLISH WALK!
一、ご挨拶は基本です
1. Greetings are basic!
二、ムカつく午後は深呼吸
2. Take a deep breath in an annoying afternoon!
三、優雅な大人気取りましょう
3. Let's act like elegant adults!
四、怒れる人は甘えてる
4. People who get angry are just being spoiled!
甘い今度のソワレ...
A sweet soirée next time...
甘い温度のソファー
The sofa with a sweet temperature...
ミルクなささやきは
The milky whisper...
無限ループする愛
Is an infinite loop of love.
イメージして
Imagine it!
街を飛び跳ねよう
Let's fly and jump in the town!
すまし顔で無視のほっぺたに
With a straight face, on the cheek of the bug,
意外なお願いが詰まってる
Unexpected requests are packed inside.
誰も知らないストーリー恐れないで
Don't be afraid of a story no one knows,
まっすぐゴールを突きつめましょう
Let's pursue our goal straight to the end!
パンパンパン パン パン
Pan, pan, pan! Pan! Pan!
遠いあこがれヘヴン
To the distant, yearned-for heaven,
時々見失う
Which I sometimes lose sight of,
無念・涙のかけら
These fragments of regret and tears...
イレースしよう
Let's erase them!
ユーウツ片付けよう
Let's clean up this depression!
揺れる想いの下の果肉には
Underneath these swaying feelings, in the pulp,
恋の美味しさだけふくらんでる
Only the deliciousness of love is swelling up.
凄いメニューを作ると野望なら
If our ambition is to make an amazing menu,
まっとうにフルーツはぐくみましょう
Let's cultivate our fruits squarely!
抱きしめたいんだ!
I want to hold you!
かみしめたいんだ!
I want to savor it!
おどかしたいんだ!
I want to startle you!
今は我慢しよう
For now, let's hold back,
修行しよう
Let's practice,
気合いしよう
Let's gear up!
COOLISH WALK
パンパンパン パン パン
Pan, pan, pan! Pan! Pan!
フレンズ
[Song: Friends]
口づけをかわした日は
On the day we shared our first kiss,
ママの顔さえも 見れなかった
I couldn't even look my mom in the face.
ポケットのコイン集めて
Gathering the coins in our pockets,
ひとつずつ 夢を数えたね
we counted our dreams one by one.
ほら あれはふたりの かくれが
Look, that was our hiding place,
ひみつのメモリー
our secret memory.
どこでこわれたの oh フレンズ
Where did we go wrong, oh friends?
うつむく日は みつめあって
On days we felt down, we gazed at each other,
指をのばしたら oh フレンズ
and when I reached out my fingers, oh friends,
時がとまる 気がした
I felt as if time had stopped.
ねえ 君は覚えている
Tell me, do you still remember
夕映えによく似合うあの曲
that song that suited the sunset so well?
だまりこむ君がいつも
Though you, who always fell silent,
悲しくて 口ずさんだのに
would hum it whenever you felt sad.
今 時は流れて
Now, time has passed,
２人は ちがうメロディー
and we are on different melodies.
２度ともどらない oh フレンズ
We can never go back, oh friends.
他人よりも 遠く見えて
You seem further away than a stranger.
いつも走ってた oh フレンズ
We were always running, oh friends.
あの瞳が いとしい
Those eyes of yours are so dear to me.
どこで こわれたの oh フレンズ
Where did it break, oh friends?
うつむく日はみつめあって
On the days we looked down, we stared at each other
指を つないだら oh フレンズ
When we linked our fingers, oh friends
時が とまる気がした
I felt time stop
2度と もどれない oh フレンズ
We can never go back, oh friends
他人よりも 遠く見えて
We looked further apart than strangers
いつも 走ってた oh フレンズ
We were always running, oh friends
あの瞳が いとしい
Those eyes were so dear
Chu chu yeah!
Please me!
Without you!
あー！なんてことだ 些細な過ちだ
Ah! What a thing, a trivial mistake
自分のことに タララッタラッタ手焼く
I'm fiddling with my own affairs, tara-ratta-ratta
どうして突然？ 逃げ切ったっていいでしょ？
Why suddenly? It's fine to run away, right?
だけどなんだか気まぐれモードになり
But somehow I'm in a fickle mode
そんな気分になっちゃって
And got into that kind of mood
始まりはそんな風で
The beginning was like that
つまりはらしくないようで
In short, it didn't seem like me
でも今じゃ扉開けてほら
But now I open the door, look
声が聴こえるよ さあ！行こう！
I can hear your voice, come on! Let's go!
どこへでも
Anywhere
僕は君の翼に なれる勇気があるよ！
I have the courage to become your wings!
(Please stay with me)
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
I'm not afraid of any trials, because I have that magic
（なんてったってコングラッチュレーション！）
(Whatever you say, congratulations!)
初めて出会う世界に 花束を贈ろう
Let's give a bouquet to the world we meet for the first time
(Made in society)
ただこの瞬間結ばれるよ
Just in this moment, we are connected
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーション？
A mismatched communication?
でも別に構わない
But I don't really care
明日から平和なら！
If it's peaceful from tomorrow on!
いっくよー！
Let's go!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
いけるビート弾く僕ら
Playing the driving beat, we are...
手を叩いて！
Clap your hands!
Yeah!
無限のリズムで弾むみんな
Everyone bouncing to the infinite rhythm!
Yeah!
どこでだって
Wherever we are,
僕は君の翼に
I will become your wings...
なれる勇気があるよ
...I have the courage to do so.
どんな試練も怖くない
I'm not afraid of any trials,
その魔法があるからね
because we have that magic.
君と出会い 世界は
Meeting you, the world...
花束に溢れた
...overflowed with bouquets of flowers.
ただその瞬間の すべてが宝物だよ
Just that single moment, everything is a treasure.
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーション
Awkward communication,
でも別に構わない
but I don't really mind,
明日が平和なら
as long as tomorrow is peaceful.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ピースピース！
Peace, peace!
いちばんうれしい いつも
The happiest, always...
Chu!
はーい！ありがとうー！
Yay! Thank you so much!
やりきったー！
We did it!
やりきりましたー！
We did our best!
ねね、間違えたけど、多分気づかれてないから大丈夫！
I made a mistake, but I'm sure no one noticed, so it's fine!
よかった、私も間違えました！
Thank goodness, I made a mistake too!
あ、間違えた？大丈夫、みんな大丈夫！
Oh, you did? It's fine, we're all fine!
あ、あ、間違えた？あははは、でもみんなあってる、大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫！
Ah, wait, did you make a mistake? Ahaha, but everyone was in sync, so it's fine!
えー、というわけで今日はねねの誕生日の記念ライブに、かわいい後輩二人に来てもらいました！
So, for Nene's birthday concert today, I invited these two cute juniors to join me!
ねね先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Nene-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！ありがとうー！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
リアルねねち！
Real Nenechi!
リアルねねち！いや、いい！
Real Nenechi! Wow, this is great!
いや、変な動き求められてる、おきに、おきに。
Wait, they're asking for weird movements. My favorite, my favorite.
曲より動いてるから、今めっちゃ息切れしましたよ。
We moved more than the song required, so I'm completely out of breath now.
でも、嬉しいですよ、呼んでいただいて。本当に嬉しい。
But I'm really glad you invited us. I'm so happy.
ね、本当に。踊ってくれると思わなかった。
Yeah, really. I didn't think you'd dance with us.
いや、二人のライブ見てから、完成度が高すぎて一回呼ぼうと思ったけど、やっぱやめようかなって思って。
Well, after seeing your lives, the quality was so high. I thought about inviting you, but then I thought maybe I shouldn't.
なんでよ！なんでよ！一緒にやろうよ！
Why?! Why?! Let's do it together!
一緒にできないと思って、でも今回頑張っちゃいました！
I thought we couldn't do it together, but I did my best this time!
いやー、よかったです！嬉しい！
No way, we're so glad! We're so happy!
デビューしてからの目標が、先輩と一緒にステージで歌って踊ることだったから...
Since my debut, my goal has been to sing and dance on stage with my senpai...
それが今日叶ったんです！
And that dream came true today!
えー！本当に嬉しい！よかった！
Aw! I'm so happy to hear that! I'm glad!
初めてのステージで歌えた！よかったー！
We sang together on stage for the first time! I'm so glad!
やったー！
Yay!
えー、じゃあ、ちょっと最後に可愛くポーズ決めて、写真撮って終わりにしようかなと思います。
Alright, then let's strike a cute pose at the end, take a photo, and wrap things up.
可愛くですね！わかりました！
A cute pose, right? Got it!
全力で、みんなそれぞれ、可愛いポーズね！
Do your absolute best, everyone make your own cute pose, okay?
フリじゃないよ！可愛くだね！アイドルらしく！
It's not a setup! Just cute, right? Like idols!
いっせーのーで！
Ready, set, go!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ちょっと待って！可愛いのはどれ！？裏切ったな！？
Wait a minute! Which one is cute?! You betrayed us, didn't you?!
Realize!
[Song: Realize!]
無口なハート開いたら
If you open your quiet heart...
進もう 声合わせて
...let's move forward, our voices in harmony!
キラキラしている自分を
The sparkling version of myself...
掴もう 大好きなことしよう
...let's seize it and do what we love!
勝ち負けだなんて関係ないともがいて
Struggling, saying winning or losing doesn't matter,
さあ 手と手繋いで
now, hand in hand...
Hey!
旅を始めよう
...let's start our journey!
Hey! Let's go! Party time!
1, 2, 3, Realize! 飛び立とうみんなで
1, 2, 3, Realize! Let's take off together!
絶対諦めたくないから
Because we absolutely don't want to give up!
Let's dream do my best! 明日はきっと輝いてる
Let's dream, do my best! Tomorrow will surely be shining!
力合わせて ときめき探して
Combining our strength, searching for excitement,
いつか行こうよ プリパラ
let's go to PriPara someday!
くよくよしている自分を
The worrying version of myself...
変えよう みんなが待ってるよ
...let's change it, everyone is waiting for you!
どんな壁だって
No matter what wall stands in our way...
ねえ 問題ないじゃない
Hey, there's no problem, is there?
さあ 勇気を出して Take flight
Come on, find your courage and take flight!
夢が始まる
Our dream is beginning!
3, 2, 1, Let's go!
Let's dance, fly with me 未来へ
Let's dance, fly with me to the future!
ずっとみんなで
Always together with everyone,
絶対手放したくないから
because I never want to let it go!
Let's sing! Do my best! 明日はもっと輝いてる
Let's sing! Do my best! Tomorrow will be even brighter!
希望を掲げて
Hold up our hopes,
ドキドキ探していく
and we'll search with thumping hearts.
私たちのプリパラ
For our PriPara!
うまく行かない日とか
On days when things don't go well,
すれ違いばかりで
and we only pass by each other,
ダメになりそうな時は一緒に
when things feel like they're falling apart, together...
歌うとっておきの
...let's sing our special...
夢を叶えよう
...and make our dreams come true!
笑顔 笑顔 受け取って
Please accept our smiles, our smiles!
そう 一緒に歌いたい
Yes, I want to sing together!
ねえ 一緒に踊りたい
Hey, I want to dance together!
絶対諦めないよ
I will absolutely never give up!
Let's go! Let's dance, fly with me 未来へ
Let's go! Let's dance, fly with me to the future!
ずっとみんなで
Always together with everyone,
絶対諦めたくないから
because I absolutely don't want to give up!
Let's sing! Do my best! 明日はきっと輝いてる
Let's sing! Do my best! Tomorrow will surely be shining!
力を合わせて
Let's combine our strength,
トキメキ探していく
and search for that excitement.
掴み取ろうプリパラ
Let's seize our PriPara!
はーい！
Hello everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Let's dance!
ねねね！
Nene-ne!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ちょっとコメントと30秒くらい差があるんだって
Apparently, there's about a 30-second delay with the comments.
そうなんだ
Oh, is that so?
一方的に話しかけること...
So we're just talking to them one-sidedly...
お邪魔してます
Thanks for having us!
ありがとう
Thank you!
いや、マジでさ、Realize!...
No, seriously, "Realize!"...
本当にこの曲、もうめちゃくちゃ緊張して...
...this song really made me so incredibly nervous...
メン限、メン限！もうメン限にしよう！
Members-only stream, members-only! Let's save it for the members-only stream!
後であるから
We'll do it later.
おまる、ちょっと飛べるようになったの
Omaru learned how to fly a little bit!
メン限で教えて
Tell us about it in the members-only stream.
見てねー！
Make sure to watch!
みんな見てねー！
Everyone, make sure to watch!
後でまた会いましょう
Let's meet up again later!
時間ない、時間ない！
We have no time, no time!
ポーズ！ポーズ撮って！
Pose! Strike a pose!
面白いポーズ撮って
Strike a funny pose!
3, 2, 1...
うわぁー！
Raaaah!
無理無理無理無理！
No way, no way, no way, no way!
君セン！って 私たち始めない？
Shall we start "Kimi-sen!"?
なんてね
Just kidding!
トーストかじって 交差点でぶつかる
Biting on toast and bumping at an intersection...
そういうんじゃないけど 予感はしてたよ
It wasn't exactly like that, but I had a premonition.
きっとね 運命だね 会えるって信じてた
Surely it's destiny, I believed we would meet.
君専用の笑顔 いっぱいオッケー
An abundance of smiles, okay!
愚痴が出たり
Complaining,
ため息ついたり
or letting out sighs...
あるよね わかるよ
That happens, right? I understand.
君が寂しくて 泣いてるなら
If you are lonely and crying,
イライラしてたまらないなら
or if you're so frustrated you can't stand it,
あたしの出番だな その手をとって連れていくよ
then it's my turn! Take my hand and I'll lead you away!
ようこそ 素敵な世界へ
Welcome to a wonderful world!
もう いっそ全部 忘れちゃえ
Just forget about everything else already!
とりあえずは あたしだけ見て 底なしの沼だぞ
For now, just look at me! It's a bottomless swamp, you know!
ちょっと 考えられないくらい
To the point where you can't even think,
愛をあげる
I'll give you my love.
君が好きだ
I love you!
君セン！って 私たち始めない？
Shall we start "Kimi-sen!"?
なんてね
Just kidding!
どうやらフラグは まだ立っていないみたいだ
It looks like the flag hasn't been raised yet.
どんなの気にしない 一直線に進め
I don't care what kind it is, go straight ahead!
きっとね 安定だね お決まりの２ショット
Surely, it's stable. Our usual two-shot photo.
二人きりの空間 ３、２、１、OK！
Our private space, 3, 2, 1, OK!
舞い上がっちゃって
I got so caught up in the moment,
あとで反省会
and will have a self-reflection meeting later.
あるよね わかるよ
That happens, right? I totally get it.
脳内占拠して 眠れないなら
If it occupies your mind and you can't sleep,
そわそわして たまらないなら
If you are so restless you can't stand it,
いつだって おいでよ
You can always come over.
少しずつ積み上げてゆこう
Let's build it up, bit by bit.
ようこそ 無限のパラダイムへ
Welcome to our infinite paradigm!
もう いっそ ずっと 一緒にいよう
Let's just stay together forever.
とことんまで 笑っていてね
Keep smiling all the way to the end.
もっと 知ってほしいんだぞ
I want you to know even more about me!
ちょっと掴んだ シャツの裾
Slightly grabbing the hem of your shirt.
最上級を プレゼントしよう
Let me present you with the highest level of love.
深く考えなくてもいいよ
You don't have to think too deeply about it.
ただ 楽しいを 続けよう
Let's just keep the fun going.
繋いだ今日が 明日になってゆくんだ
The today we connected will become tomorrow.
よーそろー 全速前進で
Yosoro! Full speed ahead!
とんでもない景色 見に行こう
Let's go see some extraordinary scenery.
乗りかかってる 自覚あるでしょ？
You realize you're already on board, right?
さんざん そこらの 遊びじゃもう
With just any old game,
満足できないくらい
to the point where you can't be satisfied anymore,
夢中になれる 夢中にさせる
you can get hooked, I'll make you obsessed.
ようこそ 素敵なテーマパークへ
Welcome to a wonderful theme park!
もう いっそ 全部 忘れちゃえ
Why not just forget everything else?
リア友は 私だけ見て
My real-life friends, look only at me.
おとなしくするの 無理だぞ
It's impossible to behave quietly!
ちょっと考えられないくらい
To the point that's almost unthinkable,
愛をあげる 君が好きだ
I'll give you my love, I love you.
時間なんて 関係ないさ
Time doesn't matter anyway.
いま立って ほら 雪崩れちゃうじゃん
Look, you're smiling!
手を繋いで
Hold hands,
私たち 止められない
we can't be stopped!
なんてね
Just kidding!
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
[Title: Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet]
突然降る夕立 あぁ傘もないや嫌
A sudden evening shower, ah, I don't even have an umbrella, how annoying
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
I couldn't care less about the sky's mood
季節の変わり目の服は 何着りゃいいんだろ
What should I wear during the change of seasons?
春と秋 どこいっちゃったんだよ
Where did spring and autumn go?
息も出来ない 情報の圧力
The pressure of information is so suffocating
めまいの螺旋だ わたしはどこにいる
A spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに
Even though I can hear the sound of breathing so clearly,
変だね 世界の音（ね）がしない
How strange, the world makes no sound
足りない 足りない 誰にも気づかれない
Not enough, not enough, unnoticed by anyone
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed out in a state where I couldn't even make scribbled sounds
「ありのまま」なんて 誰に見せるんだ
To whom would I show my "true self"?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
A fool like me can only sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I spill it all out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業も 何度目なんだ
How many times have I re-strung my guitar with Elixirs?
欠けた爪を 少し触る
Gently touching my chipped fingernails
半径３００ミリの体で 必死に鳴いてる
Screaming with all my might in a body with a 300-millimeter radius
音楽にとっちゃ ここが地球だな
To music, this place must be the Earth
空気を引き裂いて 空を殴るよ
Tearing the air apart, I strike the sky
何にも起きない 私は無力さ
Nothing happens, I am powerless
だけどさ その手で この鉄を弾いたら
But if I strum these iron strings with this hand,
何かが変わって見えた
it seemed like something changed.
眩しい 眩しい そんなに光るなよ
So bright, so dazzling, don't shine so much.
わたしのダサい影が より色濃くなってしまうだろ
My lame shadow will become even darker, won't it?
なんでこんな熱くなっちゃってんだ 止まんない
Why am I getting so hot? It won't stop!
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
I, an idiot, just sing
うるさいんだって 心臓
My heart is so noisy!
蒼い惑星 ひとりぼっち
Blue planet, all alone
いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
I've heard so many sounds
回り続けていく惑星
Continuing to spin, this planet...
一瞬でもいいから...あぁ 聞いて
Even for a moment is fine... Ah, listen
聴けよ
Listen to it!
わたし わたし わたしはここにいる
I, I, I am here!
殴り書きみたいな音出せない状態で叫んだよ
I shouted in a state where I couldn't produce
a sound like scribbles
なんかになりたい なりたい 何者かでいい
I want to become something, I want to become something,
anyone is fine
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
I, an idiot, just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I spill it all out to the stars?
あー！
Ah!
ねね先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Nene-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
イェい、イェい、イェい、イェい！
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
というわけで、ReGLOSSから奏ちゃんに来てもらいました！
And so, we have Kanade-chan
from ReGLOSS joining us!
イェーイ！音乃瀬奏です！よろしくお願いします！
Yay! I'm Otonose Kanade!
Pleased to meet you!
今回はねね、普段の奏ちゃんとの喋りと歌のギャップが大好きで
This time, I really wanted to...
because I love the gap between Kanade-chan's normal talking and singing!
あ、ありがとうございます！
A-Ah, thank you!
普段これじゃん？
Normally you're like this, right?
普段これだけど、歌うと急にね、なんか切ないエモいみたいな
Normally you're like this, but when you sing,
you suddenly sound so emotional and expressive.
うれしい！ねね先輩にそう言ってもらえるととっても嬉しい！
I'm so happy! Hearing Nene-senpai say that
makes me really glad!
そのイメージがめっちゃ好きで、一緒に何かそういう、ちょっとギャップが出る曲を歌いたいなと思って、お誘いしてみました
I really like that image of you,
and I wanted to sing a song together where we could show that gap,
so I invited you.
受けてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for accepting!
ねね先輩もめっちゃかっこよかったです！
Nene-senpai was also super cool!
ありがとう！最高！
Thank you! It was great!
あと何か髪の毛の色もさ
And also, like, our hair colors...
確かに！同じ金髪！
True! We both have blonde hair!
黄色からグラデーション？
From yellow, to a gradient?
そういうのもシンパシーあるかなと思って、お誘いしてみました。受けてくれてありがとう！
I thought we shared some connection there too, so I invited you.
Thank you for accepting!
こちらこそ！ありがとうございました！一緒に歌えてとても嬉しかったです！
Likewise! Thank you so much!
I was really happy to sing with you!
奏ちゃんのね、ダンスの覚え方が可愛いんだよ
Kanade-chan's way of remembering dance moves
is really cute!
え？そうですか？
Eh? Is that so?
忍者、忍者、忍者、忍者...
Ninja, ninja, ninja, ninja...
こうなって、こうなって、忍者、忍者って
Like, doing this and that, then 'ninja, ninja'
あります、忍者。練習中もめっちゃ笑顔だったよ
Yeah, the ninja move. You were smiling so much
during practice too!
えっと、じゃあ、最後に、どうしようかな
Well, then, finally... what should we do?
ギャップのある感じで、スクショタイム！
With that 'gap' feeling, let's do a screenshot time!
任せてください！
Leave it to me!
任せてくださいなの？はい、いけるかな、ねねも。ちょっとかっこいい、エモい感じで、大人っぽい感じで
You're saying 'leave it to me'? Alright, I wonder if I can do it too.
A bit cool, emotional, mature feel.
任せてください！いきますよ
Leave it to me! Here we go.
いこう！
Let's go!
おおー...
Ooh...
音！今なんて？何やった？今
The sound! What was that? What did you just do?
ちょっとかっこいい、エモい感じで...
A bit of a cool, emotional feel...
おお...おお...
Ooh... ooh...
おお...
Ooh...
桜が咲くよ
The cherry blossoms are blooming
見慣れたいつもの坂道に
On the familiar hill road I always take
あぁ 別れを
Ah, saying farewell
さよならメモリーズ
[Song: Sayonara Memories]
泣いて笑ったあの日々
Those days when we cried and laughed
なんだか昨日のことのよう
Somehow seem just like yesterday
この道はそう
This road is, yes...
未来へ続く道
...a road that continues into the future.
そんな気がしたの
That's what I felt.
例年より早い開花予想を
The early blooming forecast...
君は嬉しがってた
...you were so happy about it.
私は笑って「そうだね」って言った
I laughed and said, "Yeah, it is."
あと少ししたらもうここには戻れないのに
Even though soon, we won't be able to return here.
言葉じゃうまく言えない想いを
If I were to confess these feelings...
君に打ち明けるとしたらなんて
...that I can't put into words well...
伝えよう
How should I tell you?
最初で最後
For the first and last time.
いつか一緒に帰った道は
The road we once walked home together...
私にとって特別な思い出
...is a special memory to me.
忘れないよさよならメモリーズ
I won't forget you, Sayonara Memories.
春が来たら
When spring comes...
それぞれの道へ
...we'll go our separate ways.
また会える日を願って
Wishing for the day we can meet again.
さよなら
"Goodbye..."
小さくつぶやいた
...I whispered softly.
空はあの日と変わらず
The sky is just like that day...
青くて
...ever so blue.
だからちょっと泣けた
So I teared up a little.
わざと遠回りしたの
I took the long way home on purpose...
少しでも長く君の隣にいたくて
...because I wanted to be by your side for just a little longer.
私はおどけて「まちがえた！」って言った
I joked and said, "I made a mistake!"
君は笑うその顔が
Your face when you laughed...
眩しくて
...was so dazzling...
目をそらした
...that I looked away.
言葉じゃうまく言えない想いを
Holding these feelings I can't put into words well...
胸に抱いてこの道を歩いた
...in my chest, I walked down this road.
覚えてるあの時君は
Do you remember? At that time, you...
私の名前を呼んでくれた
...called my name.
二人夕暮れの帰り道で
On the way home, just the two of us at dusk.
忘れないよさよならメモリーズ
I won't forget you, Sayonara Memories.
出会えたこと感謝してる
I'm grateful that I met you.
初めて見た満開の桜
The first time I saw the cherry blossoms in full bloom.
あれからどれくらい変われたんだろう
How much have I changed since then?
一目見た時に思ったんだ
The moment I saw you, I thought...
この人の事好きになりそうって
...I'm going to fall in love with you.
なんでかな？わかんないよ
Why, I wonder? I don't know.
それからの毎日はとても楽しくって
The days since then were so much fun...
だけど同じくらいに
...but they were just as...
辛かったんだ
...painful.
ごめんねなんかうまく言えないよ
I'm sorry, I can't say it well.
だから私君となんていうか
So, I... how should I say it...
今のままさよならしたくないの
I don't want to say goodbye just like this.
友達のままじゃもう嫌なの
I don't want to just be friends anymore.
言おうと思ってた
I've been thinking of saying it, I have...
私君の
...about you...
君のことずっとずっと
...that I have, for a long, long time...
前から
...from before...
好きでした
...loved you.
ああやっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it.
いつだって君は嗤われ者だ
You're always someone who gets laughed at
やることなすことツイてなくて
Whatever you do, it never goes well
挙句に雨に降られ
In the end, you get rained on
お気に入りの傘は風で飛んでって
Your favorite umbrella was blown away by the wind
そこのノラはご苦労様と
A stray cat over there, as if saying "tough luck,"
足をふんづけてった
stepped on your foot
あーー
Ah...
いつもどおり君は嫌われ者だ
As always, you're someone who is hated
なにもせずとも遠ざけられて
Even without doing anything, people keep their distance
努力をしてみてるけど
You try giving it your best, though
その理由なんて「なんとなく？」で
The reason for it is just "for some reason?"
君は途方にくれて悲しんでた
You're at a loss and you've become sad
ならあたしの声を使えばいいよ
If that's the case, you should use my voice
人によっては理解不能で
Though some people might find it impossible to understand,
なんて耳障りひどい声だって
and say "What an annoying, awful voice!"
言われるけど
They might say that, but...
きっと君の力になれる
I'm sure I can be of help to you
だからあたしを歌わせてみて
So try letting me sing
そう君の君だけの言葉でさ...
Yes, with your words, and your words alone
綴って連ねて
Compose them, and bring them together
あたしがその言葉を叫ぶから
Because I'll shout those words for you
描いて理想を
Paint your ideals,
その想いは誰にも触れさせない
and I won't let anyone touch those feelings
ガラクタの声はそして響く
And so, the voice of the junk resounds
ありのままを不器用に繋いで
clumsily connecting things just as they are,
目一杯に大声を上げる
screaming at the top of my lungs!
いつからか君は人気者だ
Before you knew it, you became popular
たくさんの人に持て囃されて
fêted by so many people
あたしも鼻が高い
and I held my head up high too
でもいつからか君は変わった
But somewhere along the line, you changed
冷たくなってだけど寂しそうだった
You became cold, yet you seemed so lonely
「もう機械の声なんてたくさんだ
"I've had enough of mechanical voices!
僕は僕自身なんだよ」って
I am myself!"
ついに君は抑えきれなくなって
At last, unable to hold it back anymore,
あたしを嫌った
you came to hate me
君の後ろで誰かが言う
Behind your back, someone says,
虎の威を借るキツネの癖に！
"Even though you're just a fox borrowing the tiger's authority!"
ねえ君は一人で泣いてたんだね
Hey, you were crying all alone, weren't you?
聴こえる？この声
Can you hear it? This voice...
あたしがその誹謗をかき消すから
Because I will drown out that slander
わかってる本当は君が
I know that deep down,
誰より優しいってことを
you are kinder than anyone else
ガラクタの声はそして歌った
And so, the voice of the junk sang
他の誰でもない君のために
for nobody else but you,
軋んでく限界を超えて
creaking past its limits
二人はどんなにたくさんの言葉を
I wonder how many words the two of us
思いついたことだろう
came up with back then?
だけど今は何ひとつ思いつかなくて_
Yet now, I can't think of a single one,
だけどなにもかもわかった
but I understood everything.
「そうか、きっとこれは夢だ。
"I see, this must be a dream...
永遠に醒めない、君と会えた、そんな夢」
A dream from which I'll never wake, where I met you."
ガラクタは幸せそうな表情をしたまま
While keeping that happy expression, the junk...
どれだけ呼んでももう動かない
No matter how much you call, it won't move anymore
望んだはずの結末に君は泣き叫ぶ
At the conclusion you should have wished for, you cry out
嘘だろ嘘だろってそう泣き叫ぶ
Crying out, 'It's a lie, it's a lie!'
「僕は無力だ、
"I am powerless,
ガラクタ一つだって救えやしない」
I can't even save a single piece of junk!"
…涙に
...in tears,
ぽつり
drip
ぽつりと
by drip,
その頬を濡らす
wetting those cheeks.
その時
At that moment,
世界は
the world
途端に
suddenly
その色を
its colors
大きく変える
drastically changes.
悲しみ
Sadness,
喜び
joy,
全てを一人と
they learned everything...
ひとつは知った
...together, as one.
言葉は歌になり保存
Words became song,
リバーシブル仕様の直筆サイン入りアナザージャケット！
A reversible, hand-signed alternative cover!
どっちをね、表にして主役にしてもいいですし、
You can make either side the main cover,
なんなら2個買っていただいて両方とも表面にして、ねねとねねをがちゃんこさせてください。
and if you want, buy two and display both covers to make Nene and Nene combine!
そして、えー、こちらがついてきます。
And, uh, this also comes with it.
レコーディングブックと、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのカードがついてきまーす！
It comes with a recording book and a Hololive Official Card Game card!
ねねのね、どんな感じで歌ってたとか、ここ怒られたとか、そういうのがまとまったノートになってます。
It's a notebook that sums up how I sang, where I got scolded, and things like that.
そして、もう一つあります。なんと、こちら！
And, there is one more thing. Look at this!
ねねねのね、ねねの1st EP、グッズとして出したね、ねねのCDが復刻になります！イェーイ！
My 1st EP, "NeNeNeNeNe!", which was originally released as merchandise, will be re-released! Yay!
これね、あの、意外と、たぶん、持ってる人少ない、少ないんじゃないかなと思います。
I think surprisingly few people might have this one.
あの、今までのねねのね、あの、有名な曲たちが入っていますので、こちらの復刻版もぜひ聴いて、今回のアルバムと一緒に全曲聴いて覚えてほしいなって思います。
It contains Nene's famous songs from back then, so please listen to this re-release and learn all the songs along with the new album.
さて、さっきリミナルのMVの告知をしたと思うんですけど、どんな曲か聴きたいよね、みんな。
Now, I think I just announced the MV for "Liminal" earlier, but everyone wants to hear what kind of song it is, right?
それじゃあ、ねね、今からしっとりとやっていこうかなと思います。
So, Nene is going to perform it with a calm, gentle vibe now.
それでは聴いてください。「Liminal」。
Please listen. "Liminal".
見つめる 霞んだ瞳で
Staring with hazy eyes...
光を探して迷ってた
...lost while searching for the light.
いくつの痛みに 縛られたまま
Still bound by countless pains,
頬を伝う
streaming down my cheeks.
画面に映る私はどうして
Why is it that the me reflected on the screen...
涙の跡が消されているんだろう
...has the traces of her tears erased?
ひび割れたガラスの向こう
On the other side of the cracked glass,
笑って繕っていた
I smiled and patched things up.
誰かがいた
Someone was there.
偽物みたいだ 「ただの影だ」って
They assumed I was like a fake, "just a shadow,"...
決め付けたけど
...but...
まやかしじゃなくて
It's not an illusion.
私が私でいる理由を
The reason why I am who I am...
君の笑顔に貰っていた
...I received from your smile.
そうさ 画面の中
Yes, inside the screen,
隠せない 消えない 見えない
unable to hide, unable to vanish, unable to see.
それでも それでも
Even so, even so,
私は
I will...
君の光を追って
...chase after your light.
閉じこもる暗い 硝子の曇りを払って
Wiping away the fog of the dark glass I was locked in,
今、明日を見つけたんだ
I have now found tomorrow.
忘れたくない
I don't want to forget
君がくれたこの感情を
this feeling that you gave me.
見つめる 姿鏡の奥の
Staring into the depths of the full-length mirror,
涙の跡は見せられないけど
though I can't show the traces of my tears...
磨かれたガラスの向こう
On the other side of the polished glass,
笑って輝いていた
I smiled and shone,
いたいだけで
just wanting to be...
誰のためだっけ？
Whose sake was it for again?
声が 姿が 誰でもない気がした
My voice, my form, I felt like they belonged to no one.
「孤独だ」ってまた迷い出す
Crying "I'm so lonely," I start to wander again.
画面の奥の歪みを
The distortion deep inside the screen,
いつでも いつでも 君は
you always, always...
映す光の中に
...within the reflecting light...
名もない私の声を見つけてくれてた
...found my nameless voice.
ずっと
Always.
この声も、姿も、紛れもない私だ
This voice, this appearance, is unmistakably me.
「この声も、姿も、紛れもない私だ」
"This voice, this figure, is the real me without a doubt"
「ありのままでいいんだ」
"It's okay to be as I am"
「この気持ちは本物だ」
"This feeling is real"
縛られても
Even if I'm bound,
触れられなくても
even if I can't be touched,
君が示して
Because you showed...
くれてたから
...me the way
いつかこの「私」で
Someday with this "me"
ずっと光を手繰って
I'll keep following the light
きっと見つけ出す
Surely, I will find you
誰でもない「君」に会えるまで
Until I can meet the "you" who is no one else
境界線は
The boundary line...
すぐそこに
...is right there
そうさ 画面の向こう
That's right, beyond the screen
繋ぎたい 越えたい 触れたい
I want to connect, to overcome, to touch
それこそ それこそ
That is exactly, that is exactly...
私なんだ
...what I am
君と光になって
Becoming light with you
未だ遮る硝子の壁の先まで
Until beyond the glass wall that still obstructs
届くように
I want to smile...
笑っていたい
...so it reaches you
迷いはない
I have no hesitation
君がくれたこの感情と
with this emotion you gave me